New York State AFL-CIO Paul Cole Interviews Audio-Visual Materials 6202 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York State AFL-CIO Paul Cole Interviews Audio-Visual Materials
2006
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Cole, Paul M.
6202 AV
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Audiovisual materials.
8047143
Biographical / Historical
David Lawrence Cole was a graduate of Harvard University (BS., 1921) and Fairleigh Dickinson University (LL.B., 1924, LL.D., 1964.) Although he practiced law in Paterson, N.J. from 1926 until his death as senior partner in the law firm of Cole, Berman & Belksy, David Cole will chiefly be remembered for a distinguished career as a government arbitrator and mediator. In this field he served on numerous state and federal boards and in various governmental agencies. Cole was chairman of the New Jersey State Board of Mediation; a public member of Region 2, United States War Labor Board; and chairman of the Presidential Boards of Inquiry in the bituminous coal industry (1948) and in the longshore industry (1953, 1968). Cole was also a member or chairman of numerous Presidential Emergency Boards which settled disputes in the railroad and airline industries (1948-1958); the chairman of the conciliation service for the New York City transit service (1961-1965); director of the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (1952-1953); chairman of the New Jersey Governor's Committee on Public Utility Strike Service (1952-1953); member of the President's Labor-Management Advisory Committee (1961-1964); and member of the New York Governor's Public Employee Relations Committee (1966-1968), which established the New York State Public Employee Relations Board. Cole was also appointed as chairman of the President's Commission on Industrial Peace in 1973.
Beyond his public service, Mr. Cole was active as a counsel for employer groups in the textile industry (1926-1942) and as an impartial chairman for other labor-management contract disputes. He was also impartial arbitrator for the AFL-CIO Internal Disputes Plan (1954-1976), served as a visiting professor at the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University (1954-1955) and was Kestenbaum lecturer at Harvard in 1962. Mr. Cole was the author of INDUSTRIAL PEACE (1963).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6202: New York State AFL-CIO Paul Cole Files 6202 OH: New York State AFL-CIO Paul Cole Interviews Oral History on Minidiscs 6202 P(d): New York State AFL-CIO Paul Cole Digital Photographs
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 14, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 03, 2016
Cole, Paul; New York State AFL-CIO; AFL-CIO
8047143
- MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 1)
- MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 2)
- MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 3)
- MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 4)
- MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 5)
- MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 6)
- MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 7)
- MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 8)
- MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 9)
- USE MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 10)
- USE MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 11)
- USE MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 12)
- USE MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 13)
- USE MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 14)
- USE MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 15)
- USE MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 16)
- USE MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 17)
- USE MASTER -- Paul Cole Interview - 7/13/06 -- Interviewer: Prof. John H. Bishop, 2006 (Box 18)